<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes from the digital underground by Lngnmn</title>
    <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Notes from the digital underground by Lngnmn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lngnmn2.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About me.</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>A few words about me I am Jack&amp;rsquo;s wasted life.
I wrote a bunch of articles by an organ in the first person.
https://schiptsov.github.io/
That scene from Rocky movie Arguably the best scene in the classic Rocky (1976) movie, is when Mickey comes with an offer:
..Well, what ya need is a manager. A manager, listen to me. I know, because I&amp;rsquo;ve been in this racket for fifty years&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it all, all of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archery</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/archery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/archery/</guid>
      <description>The skill beats luck - fortune favors the prepared.
Shooting is to study the mind (observation, introspection, control). through practice and experience (not reading or watching).
The ancient practice of knowing your self.
The ancient exercise in self-discipline, introspection and self-knowing (know thyself).
Each shot reveals what you are (to you).
Each shot reveals you as a living Buddha or a tense fool.
Hitting a target with an arrow is a small vehicle; attaining enlightenment with an arrow is a big vehicle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing the annoying bug</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/bug/</guid>
      <description>I has been struggling with this very annoying bug when code blocks in the org mode are messed up badly when the global-whitespace-mode is enabled.
This global-whitespace-mode is especially important to see the actual mess which is usually invisible (like decease causing bacteria).
My &amp;ldquo;quality benchmark&amp;rdquo; is how my configuration renders Sacha.org, you know.
So, here is how to fix it.
Doom themes (as a standalone package)
(use-package doom-themes :demand :hook (after-init .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The org-mode rituals of a narcissistic busy-body</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/org-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/org-mode/</guid>
      <description>The ~org-mode~ package is abused and misused in so many ways, that it can be seen as a distinct psychological phenomena in itself.
The underlying mechanism is satisfaction (a dopamine release reward) from repeatedly doing supposedly &amp;ldquo;the right thing&amp;rdquo;, which, in turn, is the neurological basis of all repetitive religious rituals.
These &amp;ldquo;very smart&amp;rdquo; guys just maintain an elaborate system of mechanistic and semi-automated rituals to reinforce their deeply held unwarranted belief, on which their self-identification is based upon, that they are &amp;ldquo;very smart&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LLMS For Coding</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/llms-for-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/llms-for-coding/</guid>
      <description>Today https://news.ycombinator.com/ is glowing bright with AI memes and buzzwords like a Christmas tree. Everyone is there, including billion dollar corporations announcing a &amp;ldquo;CodeLama-34b&amp;rdquo; which is &amp;ldquo;designed for general code synthesis and understanding.&amp;rdquo;
First of all, I personaly do not want to rely in any part of my life on any &amp;ldquo;synthesized&amp;rdquo; (and &amp;ldquo;understood&amp;rdquo; software, and demand an explicit opt-out. Yes, yes, I know.
If I have any understanding of these subjects at all, this is a bubble and irrational exuberance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On burnout</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/burnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/burnout/</guid>
      <description>What is to be done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the underlying universal principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trading</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/trading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/trading/</guid>
      <description>Extracting the principles and the whys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why S and K are enough.</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/sk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/sk/</guid>
      <description>DESCRIPTION: Oops, I did it again.
The hack The word &amp;ldquo;implies&amp;rdquo; and corresponding arrows are grossly overloaded and have more than one subtle but distinct meanings.
We will read and interpret the &amp;ldquo;arrows&amp;rdquo; (and the word &amp;ldquo;implies&amp;rdquo;) from different formalisms differently (as an implication in terms of necessity and sufficiency and as a single discrete step of causality).
We will put the universal notion of an environment (and the corresponding Γ abstraction) from obscurity to the center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstraction barriers</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/abstractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/abstractions/</guid>
      <description>Interfaces, interfaces everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNU Emacs</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/emacs/</guid>
      <description>  The monument and a world-heritage &amp;#34;site&amp;#34;.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trading Math</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/trading-math/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/trading-math/</guid>
      <description>The concrete mathematics of trading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a semi-automated trading system</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/automated-trading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/automated-trading/</guid>
      <description>AUTHOR: &amp;lt;lngnmn2@yahoo.com&amp;gt;
Writing a semi-automated trading system is easy - just ask John Carmack to write it down for you.
Before that Eric Evans has to extract the domain knowledge using his DDD approach, and then some top mathematician, or maybe Bartosz Milewski, would build a consistent model from it.
Maybe it is even better to rather ask Simon Peyton Jones to write a matching engine, so you will have it pure-functional, with the most important parts formally proven in Coq (and then translated into Haskell code).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biological evolution and Life Itself</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/life-itself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/life-itself/</guid>
      <description>Stable intermediate building blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/remote/</guid>
      <description>Practices that work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundations</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/foundations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/foundations/</guid>
      <description>Stupid people would usually ask &amp;ldquo;why do we need all this theoretical bullshit and abstracted theories&amp;rdquo;?
The answer is, to have &amp;ldquo;the right understanding&amp;rdquo; and because of that to be able to do things &amp;ldquo;just right&amp;rdquo;.
&amp;ldquo;Just right&amp;rdquo; has many meanings and implications. Among other things it is that what has been &amp;ldquo;done right&amp;rdquo; (ideally &amp;ndash; a local optimum) does not require any further modifications.
It was indeed &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo; (right). There is nothing more to remove (or alter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The recurring patterns captured as a Monoid</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/monoids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/monoids/</guid>
      <description>The common patterns There are recurrent patterns, which has been captured in familiar &amp;ldquo;standard&amp;rdquo; abstractions.
Monoid A Set along with a composition operation, which has an identity element.
addition, for (+) identity is 0 concatenation, which is a specialization of putting together, identity is &amp;quot;&amp;quot;. List, a fundamental recursive sum-type, identity is [] Option, a specialization of empty/non-empty aspect of a List, identity is None Boolean logic, very subtle, identity is False (false imply nothing) The notion that some Boolean operations form a Monoid is very subtle, but it will emerge with conditional expressions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Rust</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/unrestanding-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/unrestanding-rust/</guid>
      <description>The Rust programming language has been hyped as a system programming language, which implies that it has to have an explicit &amp;ldquo;access&amp;rdquo; to the hardware-level abstractions, such as the Stack, the Heap and the Procedures, together with the operating system-level abstractions, such as following the particular calling conventions (a set of standardized interfaces) for an &amp;ldquo;arch and OS /duo&amp;rdquo;, and to be &amp;ldquo;aware of&amp;rdquo; the ABIs in general.
Overview Rust is, in principle, an imperative language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The simplest self-publishing workflow</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/the-simplest-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/the-simplest-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is the simplest but smart self-publishing workflow.
org-mode -&amp;gt; ox_hugo -&amp;gt; hugo -&amp;gt; static html -&amp;gt; git commit -a -&amp;gt; git push -&amp;gt; github pages
Everything is according to the universal principles of being almost &amp;ldquo;pure functional transformations&amp;rdquo; of a structured and decorated text, together with version control, which provides sort of immutability (of the previous versions).
At each stage or step we delegate some aspect to an appropriate external vendored tool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
