<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bullshit on Notes from the digital underground by Lngnmn</title>
    <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/tags/bullshit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bullshit on Notes from the digital underground by Lngnmn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:59:05 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lngnmn2.github.io/tags/bullshit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some Final Words</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/some-final-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/some-final-words/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, it seems like this is the time to somehow sum up the current AI hype (way through the roof) and the immediate and long term &lt;em&gt;consequences&lt;/em&gt; of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, a proper education &amp;ndash; studying the fundamental underlying principles instead of particulars &amp;ndash;  which used to be an unofficial mantra of MIT, pays off again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One just sets particular constraints to a coding LLM and use it as a whole-data-center-powerful &lt;em&gt;constraint satisfaction engine&lt;/em&gt; that spews out a slop, which then can be used for rapid prototyping and minimal-viable products. The properly constrained slop can even be used as the basis of a project, which then undergo proper &lt;em&gt;continuous improvement&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;refinement&lt;/em&gt; by a human expert (who knows the &lt;em&gt;whys&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new Brahmanas</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/the-new-brahmanas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/the-new-brahmanas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think I have seen this before. Once in Varanasi, wandering around book stalls (most titles already &amp;ldquo;tourist books&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ndash; oversimplified and westernized &amp;ldquo;tantric&amp;rdquo; bullshit), I found a whole book by some  local publisher which describes in a minute details one single Brahmanic ritual (an elaborate sacrifice) which last almost a whole day. Hundreds of ingredients are being burn in a precise sequence, or rather a simphony of chants. motions, gestures (mudras) and many other elaborate details. The priests (brahmans) definitely knew what they are doing and why exactly this way is the only proper way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bullshit, bullshit, bullshit</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/bullshit-bullshit-bullshit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/bullshit-bullshit-bullshit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, things begin to move a lot faster and much bigger, and there is something to realize about this unpreceded AI bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will consider only the underlaying fundamental principles, not the particular implementation details, &amp;ldquo;architectures&amp;rdquo; and what not..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four major aspects to any LLM model &amp;ndash; the training process, the &amp;ldquo;architecture&amp;rdquo; (the structural shape) of a model, the &amp;quot; post-training tuning&amp;quot; (lobotomy) of the model and the inference process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergence Of A New Cult</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/emergence-of-new-cult/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/emergence-of-new-cult/</guid>
      <description>The Tantra of vibe coding</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
