<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Neovim on Notes from the digital underground by Lngnmn</title>
    <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/tags/neovim/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neovim on Notes from the digital underground by Lngnmn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:03:13 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lngnmn2.github.io/tags/neovim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Everything is so over (broken)</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/everything-is-so-broken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/everything-is-so-broken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the major human psychological fallacy is to &amp;ldquo;naturally&amp;rdquo; assume that other people are more or less the same as you, just a bit mire weird. This is bullhit. Some of them are way off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is something callled a built-in (or native) package manager for  &lt;code&gt;Neovim&lt;/code&gt;  in development. Have you ever tried it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that this is not just an editor, this is a whole &amp;ldquo;ancient&amp;rdquo; tradition (which goes all the way back to hardware terminals and math majors as a synonym for a programmer) with an associated culture, and even religious zealots, which insist on purity, minimalism and even avoidance of plugins (sort of veganism).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degens, please</title>
      <link>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/degens-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lngnmn2.github.io/articles/degens-please/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear f*cking degens, for Christ sake, try to understand what are you doing and why, once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I start &lt;code&gt;neovim&lt;/code&gt; with a simple, almost default &lt;code&gt;LazyVim&lt;/code&gt; config it starts to download a new copy of the &lt;code&gt;haskell-language-server&lt;/code&gt; using &lt;code&gt;ghcup&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, try to understand that this version of &lt;code&gt;haskell-language-server&lt;/code&gt; almost certainly won&amp;rsquo;t work with an installed &lt;code&gt;GHC&lt;/code&gt;, it works only with the version it has been compiled with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
